Guide to the William F. Baxter Committee Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William F. Baxter committee records
1966-1973
SC0420
Baxter, William F., 1929-1998
3 Linear feet
Minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, press releases, clippings, and other items pertaining to Baxter's work as chair of the Committee on Research Policy as well as his work with the Provost's Committee on Economics, the Presidential Search Committee, Committee on Planning and Search in the Dept. of Economics, and the Stanford Campus Homeowners Association. Collection also includes clippings and press releases pertaining to student unrest at Stanford, 1968-1971.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of William F. Baxter, 1986.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
William F. Baxter earned his a.b. at Stanford University in 1951 and his j .d. at Stanford Law School in 1956. He has been on the Stanford Law School faculty since 1960. From 1966 to 1969 he was chairman of the Academic Council's Committee on Research Policy which considered University policy on research contracts and grants in regard to their impact on the University as a whole. One of its directives was to conduct a continuing review of problems relating to classified research.
Description of the Collection
This collection documents Baxter's work on university committees, primarily the Academic Council's Committee on Research Policy. The records ,which date from 1966 to 1973, include minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, press releases, and clippings. Other committees represented are the Provost's Committee on Economics, the Presidential Search Committee, Committee on Planning and Search in the Department of Economics, and the Stanford Campus Homeowners Association. The collection also includes clippings and press releases pertaining to student unrest at Stanford, 1968-1971.
Access Terms
Baxter, William F., 1929-1998; Stanford Campus Homeowners Association.; Stanford University. Academic Council. Committee on Research Policy.; Stanford University. Department of Economics.; Stanford University. Office of the Provost. Committee on Economics.; College students--Political activity.; Education, Higher--Research.; Federal aid to research.; Student movements--California.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Stanford Student Conflict 12/28/68-4/29/69, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Student Conflict 5/19/68-10/20/68 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Student Conflict 5/1/68-5/18/68, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student Conflict 6/13/69-9/15/69, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Conflict 5/1/69-6/5/69, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Current Events 6/26/70-12/21/70, 1970-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Current Events 5/2/70-6/25/70, 1970-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Current Events 9/1/69-5/1/70, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Current Events 12/15/71-1/18/73, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Current Events 4/7/71-12/10/71, 1971-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Current Events 1/1/71-4/7/71, 1971-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Research Policy [CRP]-The Sapirstein Affair (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Provosts' Committee on Economics (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Provosts' Committee on Economics (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Provost's Committee on Economics (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Candidates Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Presidential Candidates Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Presidential Candidates Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Presidential Candidates Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Presidential Committee (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Selection Budget (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ecomomics Search Committee (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Economics-Chairman Search Committee (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CRP: May 1969-December 1, 1971, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CRP: 4/23/69-4/29/69, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - CRP: 4/9/69-2/22/69, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - CRP: 1/1/69-4/4/69, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - CRP: Private Restraints (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Extra Copies and Ribbon-University Patent Policy Document (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CRP: Patent Matters (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CRP: Patent Matters (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - CRP: Patent Matters (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CRP: Patent Matters (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts IV 4/19/68 - 7/2/68 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts IV 7/5/68 8/30/68, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Classified Research at Stanford; Report of 11/4/68, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts V 10/28/68- 4/14/69, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts V 9/10/68 - 10/24/68, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts VI 5/ 22/69 - 12/17/69, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts VI 3/21/69 - 5/16/69, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts VI 1/1/69 - 3/18/69, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Homeowners Association (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Homeowners Association (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - CRP: Minutes (Includes Rough Drafts) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CRP: 8/1/69-1/15/70, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CRP: 5/1/69-7/30/69, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts II 9/20/67 - 12/27/67, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts II 7/11/69 - 9/15/67, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts 5/18/67-6/27/67, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts 2/13/67-5/16/67, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts 8/3/66-2/7/67, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts III 2/14/68 - 4/1/68, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - CRP: Subcommittee on Classified Contracts 12/29/67 - 2/28/68, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - CRP: 9/30/66-12/27/66, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CRP: 6/20/66-10/7/66, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CRP: 6/19/67-9/15/67 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CRP: 1/5/67-6/9/67, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CRP: 3/11/68-8/14/68, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CRP: 10/4/67-1/5/68, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CRP: 9/1/69-12/31/68, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)